Time to get up. man.
All right. Dad.
Come on.
Should be here soon.
♪ Go marching in
♪ Oh. when the saints
Go marching... ♪
I think I should make a list.
Uh. what do mean?
For your birthday gifts?
Yeah.
Well. you know you're only getting
a couple of things. right?
Yeah. I know.
Just to look at and study.
so I can choose better.
Okay. well. that's smart.
Yeah. make a list.
Can you spell everything
you're thinking of?
I think so.
All right.
That's good.
How you doing in here. man?
Okay.
Can we go to the park today?
After?
Um. No. I gotta
go to Oakland.
Well. uh...
maybe. We'll see.
Give me a kiss.
I'll talk to you later.
Excuse me.
Oh. Excuse me. uh...
when is. uh. somebody
gonna clean this off?
And... And...
And the Y?
The Y. We talked
about this.
It's an I in "happiness."
There's no Y in "happiness."
It's an I.
I'm Chris Gardner.
I met my father
for the first time
when I was 28 years old.
And I made up my mind
as a young kid
that when I had children.
my children were gonna know
who their father was.
This is part of my life story.
This part is called
"Riding the Bus."
What's that?
It's a time machine. isn't it?
Seems like a time machine.
That seems like a time machine.
It's a time machine.
Take me with you.
This machine...
This machine on my lap...
This guy. he has a time machine.
He... He... He travels.
He travels in the past
with this machine and...
it is not a time machine.
It's a portable
bone-density scanner.
A medical device
I sell for a living.
Thank you for the opportunity
to... To discuss it with you.
I appreciate it.
We just don't need it. Chris.
It's unnecessary.
And expensive.
Well. maybe next...
Thank you.
It gave a slightly denser
picture than an x-ray...
for twice the money.
- Hey.
- Hey. baby.
What happened?
Uh... No. nothing.
Look. I can't get
Christopher today.
Oh. no. you don't. Chris.
I need...
I'm back on at 7.
I know. I have got
to go to Oakland.
So I gotta
get Christopher home.
feed him. bathe him.
get him in bed. and be back here by 7?
Yes.
And we got
the tax bill notice today.
What are you gonna do
about that?
Look. This is what
we gotta do.
You see that car?
The one with the pretty
yellow shoe on it?
That's mine.
There's no parking
near hospitals.
That's what happens
when you're always in a rush.
Thanks anyway.
Uh. very much.
Uh... Uh. maybe next quarter.
It's possible.
I needed to sell at least
two scanners a month
for rent and daycare.
I'd have to sell one more
to pay off all of those tickets
under my windshield wiper.
The problem is...
I haven't sold any for a while.
Since when do you not like
macaroni and cheese?
Since birth?
What's that?
What?
What is this?
It's a gift for Christopher.
From who?
Cynthia from work.
It's for adults.
Chris can't use it.
She didn't know.
What are you supposed to
do with it?
Make every side the same color.
Did you pay the taxes?
No. I'm gonna have to.
uh. file an extension.
You already filed an extension.
Yeah. well. I gotta
file another one.
That's...
It's $650.
I'll have it in the next month.
That means interest. right?
And a penalty?
Yeah. a little bit.
Look. why don't you
let me do this?
All right. just relax.
Okay?
Now. come here.
Calm down.
I have to go back to work.
Let's get ready for bed.
Hey. uh. put your plate
in the sink.
A few days ago I was presented
with a report I'd asked for.
A comprehensive audit.
if you will.
of our economic condition.
You won't like it.
I didn't like it.
But we have to face the truth
and then go to work
to turn things around.
And make no mistake about it...
we can turn them around.
The federal budget
is out of control.
And we face runaway deficits
of almost $80 billion
for this budget year
that ends September 30th.
That deficit is larger
than the entire
federal budget in 1957.
And so is the almost
$80 billion
we will pay in interest
this year on the national debt.
Twenty years ago. in 1960.
our federal government payroll
was less than $13 billion.
Today it is 75 billion.
During these 20 years.
our population
has only increased
by 23.3 percent...
Woo! Man.
I got two questions for you:
What do you do?
And how do you do it?
I'm a stockbroker.
Stockbroker.
Oh. goodness.
Had to go to college
to be a stockbroker. huh?
You don't have to.
Had to be good with numbers
and good with people.
That's it.
Hey. you take care.
Hey. I'm gonna let you hang on
to my car for the weekend.
But I need it back for Monday.
Feed the meter.
I still remember that moment.
They all looked so...
damn happy to me.
Why couldn't I look like that?
I'm gonna try to get home by 6.
I'm. uh. gonna stop by
a brokerage firm after work.
For what?
I wanna see about a job there.
Yeah? What job?
Uh. you know. when I...
When I was a kid.
I could go through a...
A math book in a week.
So I'm gonna go see about. uh.
a job they got down there.
Oh.
What job?
Stockbroker.
Stockbroker?
Yeah.
Not an astronaut?
Don't talk to me
like that. Linda.
I'm gonna go down
to see about this.
and I'm gonna do it during the day.
Mm-hm.
You should probably
do your sales calls.
I don't need you to tell me
about my sales calls. Linda.
I got three of 'em
before the damn office
is even open.
Do you remember that
rent is due next week?
Probably not.
We're already
two months behind.
Next... Next week
we'll owe three months.
I've been pulling double shifts
for... For four months now.
Chris.
Just... Just sell
what's in your contract.
Get us out of that business.
Linda. That is what
I am trying to do.
This is what I'm trying
to do for my family.
For you and for Christopher.
What's the matter with you?
Linda.
♪ My baby told me
♪ From the start
♪ Oh. he hung
♪ His head and cried
This part of my life
is called...
"Being Stupid."
♪ Yes. I know
Can I ask you a favor. miss?
Do you mind... if I
leave this here with you.
um. just for five minutes?
I have a meeting in there.
and I don't wanna
carry that in there
looking smalltime.
Um...
here is a dollar.
And... I'll give you
more money
when I come back out.
Okay.
Um. it's not valuable.
You can't sell it anywhere.
Um. I-I can't even sell it.
and it's my job.
All right?
♪ ...his head and cried
♪ But I know
Chris?
Yes.
Tim Brophy. Resources.
How are you?
Come with me.
Yes. sir.
Let me see if I can
find you an application
for our internship.
I'm afraid that's all
we can do for you.
See. this is
a satellite office.
Jay Twistle in the main office.
he oversees Witter Resources.
I mean. I'm... You know.
I'm just this office.
As you can see. we got a hell
of a lot of applications here...
Normally I have a resume sheet.
but I can't seem
to find it anywhere.
W-we. uh... Uh...
Um... Thank you very much.
I need to go. Um...
I'll... I'll br...
I'll bring this back.
Thank you.
Okay.
Trusting a hippie
girl with my scanner.
Why did I do that?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Like I said.
this part of my life
is called "Being Stupid."
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Don't move!
Don't move! Stay...!
Stop! Stop!
Don't move! Stop this...!
Stop the train!
Stop! Stop!
The program took just 20 people
every six months.
One got the job.
There were three blank lines
after "high school"
to... list more education.
I didn't need that many lines.
Try and sleep.
It's late.
It's a puzzle measuring
just three inches
by three inches on each side.
made up of multiple colors
that you twist and turn.
and try to get to
a solid color on each side.
This little cube is
the gift sensation of 1981.
Don't expect
to solve it easily.
Although we did encounter
one math professor at USF
who took just
30 minutes on his.
This is as far as
I've gotten on mine.
As you can see.
I still have a long way to go.
This is Jim Finnerty reporting
for KJSF in Richmond.
Hey.
Wake up.
Eat.
Bye. Mom.
Bye. baby.
Come back without that. please.
Oh. Yeah.
I'm going to.
So go ahead. say goodbye to it.
'cause I'm coming back
without it.
Goodbye and good riddance.
You ain't had to add
the "good riddance" part.
Bye. Mom.
Bye.
It's written as P-P-Y.
but it's supposed to be
an I in "happiness."
Is it an adjective?
Uh. no. Actually.
it's a noun.
But it's not spelled right.
Is "fuck" spelled right?
Yeah. that's spelled right.
But that's not part
of the motto.
so you're not supposed
to learn that.
That's an adult word
to show anger
and. um... other things.
But just don't...
Don't use that one. okay?
Okay.
What's that say on
the back of your bag?
My nickname.
We pick nicknames.
Oh. yeah?
What's it say?
"Hot Rod."
Did you have a nickname?
Yep.
What?
"Ten-Gallon Head."
Heh-heh.
What's that?
I grew up in Louisiana.
near Texas.
So everybody wears
cowboy hats. And a...
A ten-gallon's
a big hat.
I was smart back then.
so they called me
Ten-Gallon Head.
Hoss wears that hat.
Hoss?
Hoss Cartwright on Bonanza.
How do you know Bonanza?
We watch it at Mrs. Chu's.
You watch Bonanza at daycare?
Yeah.
When? When do...?
When do you watch it?
After snack?
After your nap?
After Love Boat.
I made my list for my birthday.
Yeah. what'd you...?
What did you put on there?
A basketball...
or an ant farm.
He says he's been watching TV.
Oh. little TV for history.
Love Boat?
For history. Navy.
That's... That's
not the Navy.
I mean. he... He could
watch television at home.
We're paying you $150 a month.
I-if he's gonna be
sitting around
watching TV all day.
we're taking him out of here.
Go pay more at other daycare
if you don't like Navy TV.
You late pay anyway.
You complain.
I complain.
Can you at least put the dog
upstairs in you room
or something?
Bye.
I was waiting for...
Witter Resource head.
Jay Twistle.
whose name sounded
so delightful.
like he'd give me a job
and a hug.
I just had to show him
I was good with numbers
and good with people.
Morning. Mr. Twistle.
Good morning.
Mr. Twistle. Chris Gardner.
Hi. Hi.
I wanted to
drop this off personally
and make your acquaintance.
I thought I'd catch you
on the way in.
I'd really love the opportunity
to sit and discuss
what may seem like weaknesses
on my application.
We'll start with this. Chris.
and we'll call you
if we wanna sit down.
Yes. sir. You have a great day.
You too.
Hey. Uh. yeah. how you doing?
This is Chris Gardner
calling for Dr. Delsey.
Uh. yeah. look. I'm running
a little late for a sales call.
I was... I was wondering if...
Yeah. Osteo National.
Right. Uh. we can still...?
Half an hour?
Yes. Beautiful. Beautiful.
Thank you. thank you.
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
This part of my life...
Wait!
This part here...
it's called "Running."
Hey! Hey!
Wait!
Hey! Wait!
That was my stolen machine.
Unless she was with
a guy who sold them too.
Which was unlikely...
because I was the only one
selling them in the Bay Area.
I spent our entire life
savings on these things.
It was such
a revolutionary machine.
Ooh.
Can you feel it. baby?
Oh. yeah. You got me
doing all the work.
What I didn't know
is that doctors and hospitals
would consider them
unnecessary luxuries.
I even asked the landlord
to take a picture.
So if I lost one. it was like
losing a month's groceries.
Hey. hey! Wait! Wait!
Hey! Get back here!
Hey. man. uh...
Uh. I... Uh...
Who's he?
He's that guy.
Did you forget?
Forget what?
You're not supposed to
have any of those.
Yeah. I know.
You have two now.
Hey.
Hey. Mom.
One...
two...
Two.
three!
Whoo!
That's a basketball!
Hey. hey.
What do you mean?
You don't know that
that's a basketball.
This could be an ant farm.
This... This could be a...
A microscope or anything.
No. it's not.
There. there.
All right. come on.
Open him up. Open him up.
That paper's a little heavy. huh?
Yeah. but I got it.
Yeah. you should've
seen me out there today. Uh...
Somebody. uh. stole a scanner.
I had to run the old girl down...
Whatever.
What?
Whatever. Chris.
What the hell
you got attitude about?
"Whatever" what?
Every day's
got some damn story.
Hey. hey. Roy.
Roy!
Can you beat your little rug
when nobody's out here?
There's dust and shit all over.
I'm trying to keep
a clean house.
Hey. wait a second.
Wait a second.
Listen.
Look. Linda. Relax.
We're gonna come out of this.
Everything is gonna
be fine. all right?
You said that before. when
I got pregnant. "It'll be fine."
So you don't trust me now?
Whatever.
I don't care.
Taxi!
Mr. Twistle.
Yeah. hi.
Hi. Chris Gardner.
Yeah. hi. Listen.
What can I do for you?
I submitted an application
for the intern program
about a month ago.
and I would just love
to sit with you briefly...
Listen. I'm going to
Noe Valley. Chris.
Uh. take care of yourself.
Mr. Twistle.
Actually. I'm on my way
to Noe Valley also.
Uh... how about
we share a ride?
All right. get in.
All right.
So when I was in the Navy.
I worked for a doctor
who loved to play golf. hour...
Hours every day.
And... I would actually...
perform medical procedures
when he'd leave me
in the office.
So... I'm... I'm used to
being in a position
where... Where I have to
make decisions and...
Mr. Twistle. Listen. this is...
This is a very important...
I... I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Uh.
Th... This thing's impossible.
I can do it.
No. you can't. No one can.
That's bullshit.
No. I'm pretty sure I can do it.
Mm. No. you can't.
Let me see it.
Give it here.
Oh. yeah. Oh.
Wow. you... You. uh.
really messed it up.
Heh. Sorry.
Uh... it... It looks like it...
It. uh. works around a swivel.
so the center pieces
never move.
So if it's yellow
in the center.
that's the yellow side.
Right.
If it's red in the center.
that's the... red side.
Okay.
All right. So...
You... You can slow down.
Uh. listen. we can
drive around all day.
I don't believe
you can do this.
Uh. yeah. I can.
No. No. you can't.
Yes. I can.
No. you can't.
I'm telling you.
no one can. It's tough.
See? That's all
I ever do.
Uh. uh. uh...
Y-you almost have
this side.
Holy cow.
Oh. Oh. you almost
had that one.
I'm gonna get it.
Look at that.
You're almost there.
17.10.
Oh. this is me.
Good job.
Goodbye.
Yeah. I'll see...
See you soon.
Uh. where are you going. sir?
Excuse me. sir.
Where are you going. please?
Uh... Um...
Uh. two...
A couple blocks.
Just. you know. flip around.
Okay.
Hey! Stop it! Hey!
Where are you going?!
Come here!
No! No!
No. No. no. no. no!
Hey! You asshole. Give me
my money! Give me my money.
Please stop.
Please. please. Please!
Son of a bitch.
Please! He should've paid you!
He should've paid you!
Come here!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Come here. I'll kick your ass!
I'm sorry!
Idiot.
I'll get you!
I'm going to kill you!
Hey!
Stop it. you son of a bitch!
Stop him!
The doors are closing.
Please stand clear
of the doors.
No! No! No!
No!
Hello?
Hey. Yeah.
Sorry... Sorry I couldn't
make it home on time.
Chris. I missed my shift.
Yeah. I... I know.
I'm sorry about that.
Look. um... I'm
on my way right now.
Are you all right
with Christopher?
I'm leaving.
Chris. I'm leaving.
What?
Did you hear what I said?
I have my things together.
and I'm taking our son...
and we're gonna leave now.
I'm gonna put the phone down...
Linda. Wait a minute.
Hold it... Hold...
We are leaving.
It was right then
that I started thinking
about Thomas Jefferson...
Wait. wait!
and the Declaration
of Independence...
and the part about
our right to life.
liberty and the pursuit
of happiness.
And I remember thinking:
How did he know...
to put the "pursuit"
part in there?
That maybe happiness
is something
that we can only pursue.
And maybe we can actually
never have it...
no matter what.
How did he know that?
Linda. Linda.
Hello?
Chris.
Who is this?
Jay Twistle.
Uh... Hey.
Dean Witter.
Yeah. of course. Uh...
Uh... how are you?
I'm fine. Listen. do you still
wanna come in and talk?
Yes. sir. Absolutely.
I'll tell you what.
Come on by day after tomorrow.
in the morning.
We're interviewing
for the internships.
You got a pen and paper?
Uh. Yes. Uh. yes. I do.
Um... Uh. Hold on one second.
All right.
Hello?
Chris?
Uh... Uh. go ahead. I have one.
Write this number down
so you can call
my secretary. Janice. and she
can give you all the specifics.
Yep.
Okay. 415.
415.
864.
0256.
Yeah. extension 4796.
4796.
Right. Call her tomorrow.
Yes. sir. 415-864-0256.
Okay. buddy.
All right. yes.
Thank you very much.
We'll see you soon.
864-0256.
4796. Janice.
Chris.
Hey.
Did you. uh...? Have you seen.
uh. Linda and Christopher?
No. You catch
the game last night?
No. no.
You didn't see that. 118-1... One...
Excuse me. did. uh. Linda
and Christopher come in here?
No. I haven't see them.
119-120. Double overtime.
Moons hits a three-pointer.
17 seconds left.
Wayne. Wayne. Wayne.
Can't talk to you
about numbers right now.
What's your problem
with numbers?
8642.
And you owe me money.
Yeah.
You owe me $14.
I'm gonna get that to you.
I need my money.
Fourteen's a number.
Hey. Don't you ever take my son
away from me again.
Do you hear me?
Leave me alone!
Don't take my son away
from me again.
Do you understand
what I'm saying to you?
Don't you walk away from me
when I'm talking to you.
Do you hear me?
Do you wanna leave?
Yeah.
You wanna leave?
Yes. I want to leave!
Get the hell out
of here. then. Linda.
Get the hell out of here.
Christopher's staying with me.
You're the one that dragged
us down. You hear me?
You are so weak...
No. I am not happy anymore.
I'm just not happy!
Then go get happy. Linda!
Just go get happy.
But Christopher's
living with me!
Stop!
Did you hear what I said?!
Christopher's living with me!
Hey. Come... Come on.
Let's go.
How you doing. Mrs. Chu?
Hi.
Where's Mom?
Look. just get...
Get your stuff.
But she told me she was
coming to pick me up today.
Uh... Yeah. I know.
Um... I talked to
Mom earlier.
Everything is fine. okay?
Where do I sleep tonight?
Let me ask you something.
Are you happy?
Yeah.
All right. Because I'm happy.
And if you're happy
and I'm happy.
then that's
a good thing. right?
Yeah.
Yeah. All right.
You're s... You're
sleeping with me.
You're staying at home.
uh. where you...
Where you belong. all right?
Uh...
Come on.
Christopher.
Hey. Listen. I need the rent.
Yeah.
I can't wait anymore.
Yeah. uh... I'm good
for that. Charlie.
I'm gonna get it.
Why don't you go two blocks over
at the Mission Inn motel?
It's half what you pay here.
Listen. Chris. I need you
out of here in the morning.
The hell am I supposed
to be out of here tomorrow?
I got painters coming in.
All right. All right. look.
I need more time.
No.
All right...
I'll paint it myself.
All right. but I...
I just... I gotta have
some more time...
I got my son up in here.
All right.
One week.
And you paint it.
♪ Are we really happy here
♪ With this lonely game
We play ♪
♪ Looking for words to say
♪ Searching but not finding
♪ Understanding anywhere
♪ We're lost in
A masque... ♪
♪ Masquerade
Chris Gardner?
Uh. yeah.
What happened?
Payable to
the City of San Francisco.
Does it have to be the...
The full amount?
Well. you gotta pay
each parking ticket.
Otherwise. you're staying.
This is all I got.
You verify at 9:30
tomorrow morning.
What?
Yeah. you gotta stay
until this thing clears.
No.
No. I... I can't... I can't
spend the night here.
I... I have to
pick up my son.
You verify at
9:30 tomorrow.
Sir... I have a job interview
at Dean Witter
at 10:15
tomorrow morning.
I cannot stay...
9:30 tomorrow morning.
What am I supposed to do
with my son?
Is there anyone else who can...?
I take care of him.
Maybe we can go and have
Social Services pick him up.
All right. Uh. can I make...
Have my phone call. please?
Hello.
Hey.
What do you want?
Um...
you gotta get
Christopher. uh...
from daycare.
I can't... Um...
Just keep him
for the night. and I'm gonna...
I... And. uh...
Just one night.
What happened?
I'll pick him up
from. uh. daycare... tomorrow.
I'm gonna go right...
You can just...
You can drop him off.
and I'll pick him up.
No.
Come on. Linda.
Why you...?
Why you doing that?
No. I wanna take him
to the park.
To Golden Gate...
after daycare tomorrow.
How is he?
He's fine.
All right. just... All right.
take him to the park... and...
And... bring him back.
all right?
All right. just...
bring... Bring me my son back.
Okay?
Linda?
I'll bring him back around 6.
All right. All right.
Uh... thank you.
Um...
All right.
Bye.
I'm okay?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Yes. I did.
Mr. Gardner.
This way.
It'll be right this way.
What is the word on that one?
Chris Gardner.
How are you?
Good morning.
Chris Gardner.
Good to see you again.
Pleasure.
I've been sitting there
for the last half hour
trying to come up with a story
that would explain
my being here dressed...
like this.
And... And I wanted
to come up with a story
that would
demonstrate qualities
that I'm sure
you all admire here.
like... Like earnestness
or diligence.
And team-playing.
Something.
And I couldn't think...
of anything.
So the truth is...
I was arrested for failure
to pay parking tickets.
Parking tickets?
What?
And I ran all the way here
from the... The Polk Station.
the police station.
What were you doing
before you were arrested?
I was. uh...
painting my apartment.
Is it dry now?
Uh. I hope so.
Jay says you're
pretty determined.
Oh. he's been waiting outside
the front of the building
with some 40-pound gizmo
for over a month.
He said you're smart.
Well. I like to think so.
And you want to
learn this business?
Yes. sir. I wanna
learn this business.
Have you already started
learning on your own?
Absolutely.
Jay?
Yes. sir.
How many times
have you seen Chris?
Yeah. I don't know.
One too many. apparently.
Was he ever dressed like this?
No. No. Jacket and tie.
First in your class in school?
High school?
Yes. sir.
How many in the class?
Uh. 12.
It was a small town.
I'll say.
But I was also first
in my radar class in...
In the Navy.
and that was a class of 20.
Can I say something?
Uh... Um... I'm
the type of person...
if you ask me a question.
and I don't know the answer.
I'm gonna tell you
that I don't know.
But I bet you what.
I know how to find the answer.
And I will find the answer.
Is that fair enough?
Chris.
What would you say
if a guy walked in
for an interview
without a shirt on...
and I hired him?
What would you say?
He must've had on
some really nice pants.
Chris...
I don't know how you did it
dressed as a garbage man.
but you really pulled it off.
Thank you very much.
Mr. Twistle.
Hey. now you can call me Jay.
We'll talk to you soon.
All right. so I'll
let you know. Jay.
You'll... "You'll let me know.
Jay"? What do you mean?
Yeah. I'll give you a call
tomorrow sometime...
What are you talking...?
You hounded me for this.
You stood here...
Listen. There's no salary.
No.
I was not aware of that.
My circumstances
have changed some.
and I need to be certain
that I'll be...
All right. Okay.
Tonight.
I swear. I will fill
your spot. I promise.
If you back out. you know what
I'll look like to the partners?
Yes. An ass...
A-hole.
Yeah. an ass A-hole.
all the way.
You are a piece of work.
Tonight.
There was no salary.
Not even a reasonable
promise of a job.
♪ Hello. Jesus
♪ Jesus children
One intern was hired
at the end of the program
from a pool of 20.
And if you weren't that guy.
you couldn't even apply
the six months' training
to another brokerage.
Only resource
I would have for six months
would be my six scanners...
which I could
still try to sell.
If I sold them all...
maybe we might get by.
♪ You'd better tell ♪
♪ Your story fast
♪ And if you lie
Yeah ♪
♪ It will come to pass
♪ Tell me holy
♪ Holy roller
♪ Are you standing?
♪ Like a soldier
♪ Are you standing for
Everything ♪
♪ You talk about?
♪ Over and over
♪ Say transcendental
♪ Meditation
♪ Speaks of inner
Preservation ♪
I got him.
He's asleep.
All right.
Okay. baby.
I got it.
I'm going to New York.
Uh.
My sister's boyfriend...
opened a restaurant.
and they may have
a job for me there. so...
I'm going to New York. Chris.
Christopher's staying with me.
I'm his mom. You know?
He should be with his mom.
I should have him. right?
You know you can't
take care of him.
What are you gonna do
for money?
I had an...
interview at Dean Witter
for... For an internship.
And I got it.
So I'm gonna stand out
in my program.
Salesman to intern's backwards.
No. it's not.
I gotta go.
Tell him I love him. okay?
And...
I know you'll take care
of him. Chris.
I know that.
Dean Witter.
Yes. hi.
Um...
Yes. uh. I'd like to leave
a message for...
For Mr. Jay Twistle.
Your name?
Uh... Yeah. my name
is Chris Gardner.
Uh... Uh. the message is:
Thank you very much for...
For inviting me
into the program.
Uh. I really appreciate it.
and...
I'd be very pleased
to accept your invitation.
Is that all?
Yes. that's...
That's it.
Okay.
Thank you.
Bye.
Be careful with that.
What?
Be care... Go ahead.
Are we there?
Yep.
Hey. You know
what today is?
Yeah.
What?
Saturday.
You know what
Saturday is. right?
Yeah.
What?
Basketball.
You wanna go play
some basketball?
Okay.
All right. Then we're gonna
go sell a bone density scanner.
How about that?
Wanna do that?
No.
Hey. Dad. I'm going pro.
Oh.
I'm going pro.
Oh-ho!
Okay.
Yeah. I don't know.
you know.
Uh... you'll probably be
about as good as I was.
That's kind of the way
it works. you know.
And I... I was
below average.
You know. so...
Whoa.
So you'll probably
ultimately rank...
somewhere around there.
you know. so...
I really...
You'll excel at
a lot of things.
just not this.
So I don't want you out here
shooting this ball around
all day and night. all right?
All right.
Okay.
All right. go ahead.
Hey.
Don't ever let
somebody tell you...
you can't do something.
Not even me.
All right?
All right.
You got a dream...
you gotta protect it.
People can't do something
themselves.
they wanna tell you
you can't do it.
If you want something.
go get it.
Period.
Let's go.
Dad. Why did we move
to a motel?
I told you. Because I'm...
I'm getting a better job.
You gotta trust me. all right?
I trust you.
All right. here. Come on.
come on. Come on. Keep up.
Dad. when's Mom coming back?
Dad. When's Mom
coming back?
I don't know. Christopher.
Dad. listen to this.
One day. a man was
drowning in the water.
And a boat came by and said.
"Do you need any help?"
He said. "No. thank you.
God will save me."
Then another boat came by.
Said. "Do you need any help?"
And he said. "No. thank you.
God will save me."
Then he drowned.
and he went to heaven.
And he said. "God.
why didn't you save me?"
And God said. "I sent you
two big boats. you dummy."
Do you like it?
Yeah. that's very funny. man.
Give me your hand.
Oh. Thank you very much. sir.
Yes. sir.
You got the bill of sale here.
Yes.
All the information
you'll need.
Uh. thank you very much
for your business.
Thank you.
Dr. Forrest. dial 182. please.
One hundred. 200. 20. 40.
45. 46. 7. 8. 9. 10.
Thank you.
Hey. you want one of those?
No. it's okay.
Come on. you can
have one. Which one?
You like that one? How much?
Twenty-five
cents.
This part of my life
is called "Internship."
The 1200 building is Medley
Industrial and Sanko Oil.
The building across the street
is Lee-Ray Shipping.
In a couple of weeks.
you'll get call sheets
with the phone numbers
of employees
from every Fortune 500 company
in the financial district.
You will be pooling
from 60 Fortune companies.
You will mainly be
cold-calling potential clients.
But if you have to
have lunch with them.
have breakfast with them.
even babysit for them.
you will do whatever it takes
to familiarize them
with our packages.
We need you to match
their needs and goals
to one of our many
financial plans.
In essence...
you reel them in.
we'll cook the fish.
Some of you guys are here
because you know somebody.
Some of you are here because
you think you're somebody.
But there's one guy in here
who's gonna be somebody.
That person's gonna be
the guy...
who can turn this into this.
Eight hundred thousand
in commission dollars.
You. you. help me
hand these out.
This is going to be your bible.
You'll eat with it.
You'll drink with it.
It was simple.
X number of calls equals
X number of prospects.
X number of prospects equals
X number of customers.
X number of customers equals
X number of dollars
in the company's pocket.
Your board exam.
Last year. we had an intern
score a 96.4 percent
on the written exam.
He wasn't chosen.
It's not a simple pass/fail.
It's an evaluation tool we use
to separate applicants.
Be safe. Score a hundred.
Okay. Let's take a break.
Be back in 10.
Oh. Hey. Mr. Frohm.
Hi.
Uh. Chris.
Ah. Chris. how are you?
I'm good. How you doing?
Fine. thank you for asking.
Yeah. uh. first day in there.
It was. uh. exciting.
You're not quitting on us yet. are you?
Oh. no.
No. sir. Ten-minute break.
Uh...
Pop out. get a quick bite.
and then back in there
for board prep.
Oh. man. I remember mine.
And ours were only an hour.
not three like yours.
We didn't do world markets.
we didn't bother with taxes.
and it was still
a pain in the ass.
Funny what you remember.
There was a beautiful girl
in that class.
I can't remember her name.
but her face was so...
I've seen an old friend
of mine. Uh. do... Do you mind?
No. go ahead.
Uh. good talking to you. sir.
Aah.
Hey. hey... Hey. asshole.
Yeah.
Are you all right. asshole?
Are... Are you okay?
I mean. what were you thinking?
What are you doing?
I could've killed you.
I'm trying to cross the street.
Uh... you're all right?
Yeah. yeah.
Where's my shoe?
What?
You knocked off my shoe!
I don't know
where your shoe is.
Where's my damn shoe?
I don't know.
Hey.
Did you see it?
I lost my shoe.
No. I'm sorry.
Hey. Hey. Where
are you going?
We should wait for the police.
I gotta go to work.
Hey. you just got hit by a car.
Go to the hospital.
I'm in a competitive
internship at Dean Witter.
Hey. man. you're
missing a shoe.
Oh. Yeah.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Dad.
Y-you don't have
a shoe.
Yep. I know.
Wanna know what happened?
Yeah.
I got hit by a car.
You got hit by a car?
Yep.
Where?
Uh. just right by the office.
No. where in your body?
Like. the back of my legs.
Hey. goodbye. Mrs. Chu.
Goodbye.
Where you on the street?
Y-yeah. I was running
in the street.
Don't do that.
You can get hurt.
Yeah. thanks.
I'll remember that next time.
And here I was again.
Show up early.
While qualified persons...
Qualified persons are
interested in investing
and have money to invest.
Now... Chris.
Yes. sir.
Would you get me
some coffee. please?
Favors for Frakesh.
our office manager. All day.
My name is Chris Gardner calling
for Mr. Michael Anderson.
Well. yes. sir. We're having
a lunch actually this Thursday.
Okay. next time. All right.
I'm gonna hold you to that.
Okay. yes. Thank you.
Who wants to get me a doughnut?
Chris?
Yes. sir.
Feeling underrated
and unappreciated.
Hello. Mr. Ronald Fryer.
Why. good morning to you. sir.
My name is Chris Gardner.
and I'm calling
from Dean Witter.
Yes. I have some very. very
valuable information
on what's called a tax...
Okay... Thank you. sir.
Then catch the bus by 4
to the place where
they can't spell "happiness."
Then the cross-town.
The 22 home.
Hey! Chris!
Hey. Hi. Ralph.
I'm waiting.
All right. uh.
I-I got that for you. Ralph.
I'm... I'm gonna
get that for you.
Whoever brought in
the most money after six months
was usually hired.
Yes. hello. Chris Gardner
calling for Mr. Walter Hobb.
We were all working our way up
call sheets to sign clients.
From the bottom to the top.
Yes. sir.
How are you?
From the doorman to the CEO.
Okay.
They'd stay till 7.
but I had Christopher.
I had to do in six hours
what they do in nine.
Good afternoon.
My name is Chris Gardner.
I'm calling from Dean Witter.
In order not to waste any time.
I wasn't hanging up the phone
in between calls.
Okay. Thank you very much.
I realized that by
not hanging up the phone.
I gained another
eight minutes a day.
Why. good morning to you.
my name is Chris Gardner.
I'm calling from Dean Witter.
I also wasn't drinking water.
so I didn't waste any time
in the bathroom.
Uh. yes. I'd love to
have the opportunity...
Okay... No problem at all. sir.
Thank you very much.
But even doing all this...
after two months...
I still didn't have time
to work my way up a sheet.
We're feeling really
confident about that one as well.
Walter Ribbon's office.
Yes. Hello. my name
is Chris Gardner.
I'm calling for
Mr. Walter Ribbon.
Concerning...?
Yes. ma'am. I'm calling
from Dean Witter.
Just a moment.
Hello?
Mr. Ribbon.
Uh. h-h-hello. sir.
My name's Chris Gardner.
I'm calling from Dean Witter.
Yeah. Chris.
Uh. yes. Mr. Ribbon.
I would love to have
the opportunity
to sit with you to discuss
some of our products.
And. I... I'm certain
that I could be
of some assistance to you.
Can you be here in 20 minutes?
Uh... ye... 20 minutes.
Absolutely.
Just had someone cancel.
Come now. I can give you
a few minutes before the 49ers.
Monday Night Football. buddy.
Yes. sir.
Thank you very much.
See you soon.
Bye-bye.
Excuse me.
Thank you for the...
Chris. what's up?
Hey. Mr. Frakesh.
Hey. man. do you have
five minutes?
Actually. I got a green light
from Walter Ribbon...
Because I have no minutes. I'm
supposed to present commodities
to Bromer. Could you move my
car? That'd really help me out.
It's on Samson.
half block. silver Caprice.
Just move it to the other side.
They're street sweeping.
There's spaces.
Hang on to these.
I have backups in my desk.
And you have to jimmy that.
Uh. uh... Jimmy what?!
You have to jimmy the key.
And the other doors
don't unlock.
You have to jimmy it.
Come on. I'm jimmying it.
Oh. no!
Come on. come on.
♪ People keep on learnin' ♪
♪ Soldiers...
Here's the file.
Mr. Ribbon.
Thank you.
Okay. thanks a lot.
Oh. yeah. thanks.
Great idea.
No. No. no. no. no!
♪ Powers keep on lyin' ♪
Rachel. get Ristuccia on
the phone for me. please.
♪ Keep on dyin' ♪
♪ World keep on turnin' ♪
♪ Cause it won't be too long ♪
♪ I'm so darn glad
He let me try it again ♪
♪ Cause my last time on earth
I lived a whole world of sin ♪
♪ I'm so glad that
I know more than I knew then ♪
♪ Gonna keep on tryin' ♪
♪ Till I reach
The highest ground ♪
♪ Whew
♪ Till I reach
The highest ground ♪
♪ Oh. no
♪ No one's gonna
Bring me down ♪
Hi.
I'm Chris Gardner. I have an
appointment with Mr. Ribbon.
Oh. you just missed him.
Ah. thank you.
♪ No one's gonna
Bring me down ♪
♪ Oh. no
♪ Till I reach
The highest ground ♪
♪ Oh. no
♪ No one's gonna
Bring me down ♪
♪ Oh. no
♪ Till I reach
The highest ground ♪
What's that?
Just filling out a check.
Paying some bills and a...
parking ticket.
We don't have a car anymore.
Yep. I know.
Oh. um...
I'm gonna need to take you
with me this weekend.
A couple doctors' offices.
Well...
On sales calls. okay?
Okay.
Then. possibly...
we'll go to the football game.
Really?
Uh. possibly.
All right?
All right.
Mm-hm.
Come on. finish up.
Are you sure?
I was...
Possibly.
Really?
Are you bringing it
to the game?
Yeah. I don't...
I don't wanna leave it.
And maybe we're
going to the game.
All right.
Where are we going now?
Uh. to see someone
about my job.
I don't understand.
You don't understand what?
Are we going to the game?
I said possibly
we're going to the game.
You know what "possibly" means?
Like probably.
No. "probably" means there's
a good chance that we're going.
"Possibly" means we might.
we might not.
What does "probably" mean?
It means we have a good chance.
And what does "possibly" mean?
I know what it means.
What does it mean?
It means that we're not
going to the game.
How did you get so smart?
Cause you're smart.
Are we there?
Yeah.
Mr. Ribbon.
Yes?
How are you. sir? Chris Gardner.
Dean Witter.
Oh. hi. Hi.
This is my son. Christopher.
Hi.
Hey. Christopher.
W-w-what are you
doing up here?
Uh. I came to apologize
for missing our appointment
the other day.
Oh. you didn't need to come up.
Oh. no. Actually.
we were in the neighborhood
visiting a very close friend
of ours. and I-I just wanted
to take this opportunity
to say thank you for your time.
I know you probably
waited for me.
Little bit.
I-I want you to know
that I do not
take that for granted.
Oh. come on. W-what. uh...
What's that?
Oh. this... Uh. an Osteo
National bone-density scanner.
Oh.
A company I bought into prior to
going to work at Witter.
I have a meeting
after the game.
You guys are going to the game?
Oh. yeah.
Possibly.
We're... We're going too.
I'm taking my son. Tim.
My 12-year-old.
We were just leaving. Tim!
Listen. we'll... We'll
get out of your way.
Um. again. thank you very much.
and I'm sorry
about the other day.
And I hope that we can
reschedule for later this week.
You got it.
Thank you very much. sir.
All right.
You take care. Here. come on.
Um. Say bye-bye. Chris.
Bye.
Bye. Christopher.
Hey. you guys
wanna come with us?
What. uh...?
To Candlestick?
We're going now.
Come with us.
Where are your seats?
Oh. we've...
We're... upper deck.
We got a box.
Come on.
You wanna sit in a box?
No.
Well...
It's not actually a box.
It's... It's. um...
a private section.
It's more comfortable.
You wanna go?
Okay.
Okay. Kids in the back.
Hey. why don't you just
put that in your car?
Um...
Yeah. okay...
Uh. sure. Sure.
We don't have a car.
Ah!
Oh. my G...
What happened?
I think I got stung by a bee.
You all right?
Oh. Yeah.
Goodness. I'm fine.
You're not allergic or anything?
No. no. no. Aah.
Where'd he get you?
Just. like. right at the. uh.
back of my head. Aah.
Are you okay?
Uh. yeah. I'm fine. Christopher.
Does it hurt?
Uh. Christopher. I'm fine.
Let me see.
Christopher. Sit back.
Sit back.
Thomas Jefferson mentions
happiness a couple times
in the Declaration
of Independence.
May seem like a strange word
to be in that document. but...
he was sort of...
He was an artist.
He called the English. "the
disturbers of our harmony."
And I remember standing
there that day
thinking about
the disturbers of mine.
Questions I had.
Whether... all this was good.
Whether I'd make it.
And Walter Ribbon. and
his Pacific Bell pension money.
which was millions.
Yeah!
It was a way to another place.
Wow. This is. aah...
This is the way to watch
a football game here.
Thank you very much
for this. really.
Hey. that's my pleasure. Chris.
And. uh. Mr. Ribbon.
I also wanna thank you
for giving me the opportunity
to discuss the asset management
capabilities of Dean Witter.
which we believe
to be far superior
to anything you got going
over at Morgan Stanley.
And. uh. really. I think
you're gonna be blown away.
Point blank. Dean Witter
needs to be managing
your retirement portfolio.
You know. I didn't
have any notion
that you were new over there.
I mean. I like you. but...
there's not a chance
I'm gonna let you
direct our fund.
That's just not gonna happen
anytime soon. buddy.
So... you know.
come on. relax.
Let's play the game.
Go. go. go!
Yeah!
Yes! Yes! Yeah!
Whoo!
Here you go.
All right.
I've had a few ideas
already. Absolutely.
Chris. I'll talk to you later.
Thanks you very much.
I'm gonna give you a call.
Nice to meet you. Chris.
Give me a call.
Yes. Absolutely. Thank you.
Bye.
Bye. Christopher.
♪ Morning. morning
♪ Feel so lonesome
In the morning ♪
♪ Morning. morning
♪ Mm. morning...
After four months.
we had sold all our scanners.
It seemed we were making it.
What's the...
fastest animal in the world?
Jackrabbit.
Seemed we were...
doing good.
Till one day...
that day...
that letter brought me
back to earth.
This part of my life
is called "Paying Taxes."
If you didn't pay 'em.
the government could
stick their hands
into your bank account
and take your money.
Dad.
No warning. Nothing.
It can't be too late.
That... Th... That's my money.
How is somebody just gonna...
Just take my money?
I w... I was...
Listen... I...
That's all the money
that I have.
You cannot go
into my bank acc...
No...
It was the 25th of September.
I remember that day.
Because that's the day
that I found out...
there was only
21 dollars and 33 cents
left in my bank account.
I was broke.
You dressed yet?
No.
♪ When the young man...
Chris! Chris!
Don't jerk me around.
okay. Chris?
I'm not jerking you around.
Ralph. all right?
I g... I'm gonna
get it.
I need that money now.
Not later!
When I get it.
you get it. Ralph.
Now!
Hey. What's
happening. man?
Wayne. uh... I need to...
To get that $14 from you.
I... I thought I didn't
owe you that now.
What? Why?
Why what?
Why would you think
you don't owe me my money?
I helped you move.
You drove me two blocks. Wayne.
That's 200 yards.
It's been four months. Wayne.
I need my money.
I need my money right now.
Hey. man.
I don't have it. man.
Wayne. go get my money.
I'm sorry.
Wayne. Get my mo...
I really don't. man. It's $14.
It's my $14!
Go get my money!
All of this for $14.
Get my money. Wayne.
Dad. look at me!
Dad!
Should I go?
Sure. man. Why not?
Stay here. Christopher.
Dad. look.
No. no. Stay right here.
Dad!
Did you hear what I said?
Did you hear me?
Dad. where you going?
Hey... What did
I say?
Dad!
Dad. wait!
I gotta...
I gotta get back
to the '60s. man.
That's what I wanna do.
When I was younger. I...
I wanna see Jimi Hendrix
do that guitar on fire.
Bring back my time machine!
Bring my time machine back!
Dad. where are we going?
Just be quiet.
Go get your things. Go.
Chris?
Yes.
Dr. Telm can't get back
to meet you.
I'm sorry.
Where are we going now?
Gotta. uh... We gotta
see somebody else.
I'm tired.
I know.
Um...
Doesn't seem to be. uh.
functioning...
right now.
I have to go now. Chris.
No. No. no. Uh...
Just give me a second.
I'm sure I can... I'm gonna
be able to figure it out.
Chris. Chris. Just
come back when it's working.
No. No. I... I...
I have to fix it now.
No.
Look. I'll still be putting
money into the office. then...
all right?
I really have to go. Chris.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you for your time.
I appreciate it.
I'll see you soon.
Why are our things here?
Dad.
Let's go. Come on.
Where?
Come on.
Just out of here.
Why?
We can't stay here tonight.
Yes. we can. Open the door!
Hey. Did you hear
what I said?
Let's go.
Open the door!
Hey. Did you hear
what I said? Stop it.
Stop it.
Come on.
Wayne!
Get up. Stand up.
Come on.
Where are we going?
Dad! Where are
we going?
I don't know.
It's not a time machine.
Dad.
The guy said
it was a time machine.
It's not a time machine.
He was wrong.
What guy?
The guy.
He was at the park.
He said it was a time machine.
Yes. it is.
No. it's not.
It is.
All we gotta do is push
this black button right here.
You wanna push it?
Okay.
Come on.
Come on. man.
Right here.
Wait a minute.
Where you wanna go?
I don't know.
Someplace from before.
You gotta close your eyes.
You close your eyes.
I wanna see.
All right. come on.
We'll push it together.
You gotta close your eyes.
Close your eyes.
It takes a few seconds.
Oh. my goodness.
W... Open. open.
open!
Whoa.
What is it?
Dinosaurs.
Where?
You don't see
all these dinosaurs?
Look around.
Look at all these dinosaurs.
Wow.
Do you see 'em?
Yeah.
Wait. Come on.
come on. come on.
Wait... Watch out.
What is it?
Don't step in the fire.
We're cavemen.
We need this fire.
'cause there's no electricity.
and it's cold out here. okay?
Watch out! Watch out!
Whoa! Oh. my good... A T. rex.
That's... Get your stuff.
Get your stuff.
Get... Get it...
Get up here.
We gotta find someplace safe.
Like what?
Um... we need a cave.
A cave?
We gotta find
a cave. Come on.
Okay.
Come on. come on.
Wait... Watch your
back! Look out.
Here it is. Here's
a cave. Come on.
Right here. right here.
Go. go. go.
Whoa.
Go ahead.
Get in.
Hurry. hurry. Hurry.
Are we safe?
Yeah. I think so.
Hey.
How you doing? Jay?
I'm doing good.
How you. uh. getting along?
Good. I'm good.
You doing good?
How you doing?
I'm doing great.
Where you going?
Oh. Um...
I. uh... Sacramento.
'Cause. um...
I'm trying to move
a couple guys that... From...
They're at... At PacBell. and I'm
trying to bring them over...
Get them over to us.
So they got me
going out there golfing.
Awesome.
Hey. let 'em win a round.
Deborah. Someone's
asking for you.
Where?
He's outside.
Please come with me.
Hi.
How you doing?
Um...
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
Um...
We need a room.
Just until I can...
fix this and sell it.
There's just some glasswork.
Let me stop you right there.
I wish I could help you...
This is my son. Christopher.
He's 5 years old.
Hi. baby.
We need someplace to stay.
Okay. And I would
love to help you.
but we don't take men here.
It's only women and children.
Now. he can stay here.
but you have to find
someplace else to go.
We gotta stay together.
We got... We... We're...
Okay. Okay. listen.
You gotta have someplace...
Try Glide Memorial.
The building books up at 5.
So you hurry up.
'cause there's a line.
Where is it?
Where? Come on.
E-E-Ellis
and Jones.
Hey! Hey. everybody.
We have four spots left.
and that's all.
Man.
Hey. Come on. man.
Come on.
Come on. what?
Hey. that's my spot.
Back up.
Come on. don't do this to me. Don't...
Back up!
Dad! Dad!
Stop it! Break it up!
Break it up!
Stop! Stop!
Come here! Come here!
Get out of the line.
both of you. Both of you.
I was here first. They told me
that we had to be here on time.
I got here on time.
I was in line.
I came from work. I got my son.
I was here on time.
We were here on time!
He sliced in front
of him in line.
Who did?
He did.
Come on.
Come on. Rodney.
Come on. Let's go.
Get out of line.
That's it.
No more.
What's your favorite color?
Green.
Green?
Mm-hm.
What do you like that's green?
Trees.
What else?
Holly.
Holly. What's holly?
The Christmas stuff.
Ah. Christmas
stuff.
What's that?
I guess they want us
to go to sleep.
There you go.
We gotta...
make sure Captain America's
warm in there.
Can he breathe?
He's good?
Yeah.
I gotta go work on the scanner...
Don't go.
No. no. no. I'm gonna be...
I'll be right outside the door.
All right? I'm just...
I'm gonna be right there...
I'll leave the door open
a little bit.
And I'll be able to
hear you if you call me.
I wanna go home.
But... that's why
I gotta. uh.
work on the scanner.
All right?
I'm gonna go
out there. Um...
I'm gonna leave the door open.
I'll be right up the stairs.
And...
I'll be able to hear you
if you call me.
All right?
All right.
You gotta trust me. okay?
You gotta trust me.
You gotta...
Trust you. I trust...
I trust you.
I trust...
I can't hear you.
I trust you.
All right.
Give me a kiss.
Mwah.
I'll just be a little
while. okay?
All right.
I'll be right here.
Okay.
Can you still hear me?
Yeah.
Can you hear me?
Do you trust me?
Yeah.
Like that?
Yeah. Put that one...
Then you go like that.
Is that okay?
I don't know.
What do you think?
It's good.
Let's go.
Get your stuff.
Hey. why don't you leave it?
We can't.
We're gonna have
a different room later.
Go.
Hey. Chris.
Hey. Good morning.
Mr. Frakesh.
What's up?
Work trip.
Your wife. Martha.
works at PacBell also. correct?
Yes. she does.
And you guys are both looking
to retire at about
the same time?
We'd like to retire and
maintain the same lifestyle
without paying a lot of taxes.
So basically.
you don't want nobody's hands
in your pockets but your own?
Nobody's.
Are you familiar with
tax-free municipal...?
I learned to
finish my work quickly.
I had to finish quickly.
To get in line at Glide by 5.
Come on. Come on.
No.
Come on!
♪ You're feeling all right ♪
♪ Oh-oh
Hold that bus!
Hold the... Hold the bus!
My Captain America!
Dad! Dad! Dad! Dad!
Stop it! Shut up!
Shut up!
Excuse me.
Why don't you let the lady in?
Hey. Back up.
Hey. man. that's not cool.
Back up. Back up!
Back up!
♪ You sure took me
For one bad ride ♪
♪ And even now I sit
♪ And I wonder why
Come on.
♪ And even when
I think of you ♪
♪ I stop myself
From crying ♪
Dad. we need to get it!
The important thing
about that freedom train
is it's got to climb mountains.
We all have to deal
with mountains.
You know... mountains
that go way up high.
And mountains that go
deep and low.
Amen. preacher!
Yes.
We know what
those mountains are
here at Glide.
We sing about them.
♪ Lord. don't move
That mountain ♪
♪ Give me strength to climb it
♪ Please don't move ♪
♪ That stumbling block
♪ But lead me. Lord Around it ♪
♪ My burdens
They get so heavy ♪
Yes.
♪ Seems hard to bear
♪ But I won't give up
No. no ♪
♪ 'Cause you
Promised me ♪
♪ You'd meet me at the altar
Of prayer ♪
♪ Lord. don't move
That mountain ♪
♪ Please. don't move
♪ But give me strength
To climb it ♪
When's your test?
Tomorrow.
Are you ready?
Of course.
Thank you. sir.
Hey.
How you doing?
Yeah.
So did you finish
the whole thing. or...
you have to go somewhere?
I... I have...
I have to go somewhere.
Right.
But I finished
the whole thing too.
Oh. Good.
You?
Yeah.
How'd... What... How did
you feel about the graphs?
Easy.
I struggled with the... With
the essay question on the back.
What did you write?
Essay question?
Yeah. On the back.
Hey. Chris.
Hey. Uh...
Uh. Jeff. right?
Yeah.
49ers game.
Yeah. You were gonna
give me a call.
I never actually got your number.
Oh. hey.
Here's my number.
Call me. okay?
Yes. sir. Absolutely.
Thank you very much.
Chris. You got
five bucks?
I left my wallet upstairs.
Let me. uh. run up and grab
that for you. Mr. Frohm.
No. I gotta be in CAL Bank
at 4. and I'm late.
Um...
I'll pay you back. honest.
Five... Five is good?
Five is lovely.
Thank you. Thank you.
That's it. That's
the room quota.
There's no more space.
You gotta head out.
That's it for today.
Come back tomorrow.
All the rooms are closed.
Completely full.
That's it.
Just keep heading out.
Come back tomorrow.
♪ And feeling small
♪ And tears
♪ Are in your eyes
♪ I'll dry them all ♪
♪ I'm on your side ♪
♪ When times... ♪
You like it?
♪ ...get rough ♪
♪ And friends
♪ Just can't ♪
♪ Can't be found ♪
♪ Like a bridge
♪ Over troubled waters ♪
♪ I will lay me down
Twenty. one. two. three. four.
Now. here's your bulb...
and there's your ferrite
core inductor.
How much?
Eight dollars.
What's that?
Uh. it's to repair the light.
Can I see it?
Uh...
Yeah. sure.
Just... don't break it.
Unless you wanna...
sleep in a room with me
for the rest of your life.
I don't mind.
Hm.
Yeah. you will.
Why don't you get
some sleep. okay?
Okay.
Warm enough?
Yeah.
All right.
Did Mom leave because of me?
What?
Don't... Don't even...
think something like that.
Mom left because of Mom.
And you didn't have anything
to do with that. okay?
Okay.
You're a good papa.
All right. go to sleep.
I love you.
I love you too.
So far so good. Chris.
It works.
All right. Thank you very much.
Two hundred and fifty dollars.
Four more weeks of oxygen.
One hundred.
20. 40. 60. 80. 200.
Twenty. 30. 40. 50.
Anything else?
No. This is good.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
You ready?
Yup.
Bye.
Are we going to
the church place?
No.
Where are we going then?
Probably stay at a hotel.
A hotel?
Well. just for the night.
We can go back to the cave
if you like.
Hm.
No. thank you.
Ever?
I-I hope not.
Why not?
Well. 'cause some things are fun
the first time you do 'em.
and then not so much the next.
Like the bus?
Yeah. Like the bus.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't laugh. should I?
He doesn't know
where it is though.
Didn't you ever
want to have a home
of your own like other people?
Sometimes when
we're moving at night.
we pass houses with
lights and people.
Sometimes you can
hear them laugh.
The next day... after work...
we just went to the beach.
Far away from anything.
Everything.
Just Christopher and me.
Did you see me?
Yep.
Far away from...
buses and noise
and a constant disappointment
in my 10-gallon head.
And myself.
Chris. thank you very much.
Thank you. Dean.
Take care. Chris.
Hey. you made the right moves here.
Thanks. Chris.
Because when I was young
and I'd get an A
on a history test
or whatever...
I'd get this good feeling
about all the things
that I could be.
And then I never became
any of them.
Hey. Chris.
Hey.
How are you doing. Jay?
I'm doing fine.
Rumor has it you signed
31 accounts for us
from Pacific Bell.
Yeah. I. uh...
met some guys at a ball game.
got some cards
I've been working.
I guess.
So... one more day.
Getting nervous?
No. I'm... I'm okay.
Yeah?
Listen. whatever happens...
you've done
a fantastic job. Chris.
I mean that.
Take care of yourself.
Yes. Mr. Johnson.
Chris Gardner. Dean Witter.
Yes. sir. Just. uh. calling
to thank you very much
for your support
at last month's seminar.
Uh... Oh. yes. sir. Absolutely.
Yes. sir.
No. sir. that's it.
Thank you very much.
Bye-bye.
Chris.
Come.
Hi. Chris.
Mr. Frohm. Good to see you.
Nice shirt.
Heh. Thank you. sir.
Chris.
Hi. Jay.
Chris. Sit down.
please.
I thought I'd. uh...
wear a shirt today.
Um... you know.
being the last day and all.
Well. thank you.
Thank you.
We appreciate that.
But. um...
wear one tomorrow though. okay?
Because tomorrow is going
to be your first day.
If you'd like to
work here as a broker.
Would you like that. Chris?
Yes. sir.
Good. We couldn't
be happier.
So...
welcome.
Was it as easy as it looked?
No. sir. No.
No. sir. it wasn't.
Well...
Good luck. Chris.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Welcome. sir.
Oh. Chris.
I almost forgot.
Thank you.
This part of my life...
This little part...
is called "Happiness."
Christopher. Come here. man.
Come here.
So... how many...
planets are there?
Um... seven.
Seven?
Mm-hm.
Nine.
Okay.
Um...
Who's the king of the jungle?
Gorilla.
A gorilla?
The gorilla?
Mm-hm.
No. Lion.
Oh. yeah.
Lion. lion. lion.
Hey. Dad. listen to this.
Knock. knock.
What? Who's there?
Shelby.
Shelby who?
♪ Shelby coming around
The mountain when she comes ♪
Knock. knock.
Who's there?
Nobody.
Nobody who?
Oh.
Now that's funny.
I like that one.
♪ Ba-da-ba-dum
♪ Ba-da-ba
♪ Ba-da-ba-ba
♪ I build a fence around you
♪ In a father's way ♪
♪ I try to feel what it is
You're goin' through ♪
♪ 'Cause I've played
Many ways ♪
♪ When you grow
♪ How much will it take
To slow you down ♪
♪ Half the way
♪ Do my best to please you
♪ And I do what's right ♪
♪ I try to find each word
That I'll say to you ♪
♪ When you come home tonight
♪ And if so
♪ How hard will we cry
♪ Before our sun fades away
♪ And one day when the fence
Is not so high ♪
♪ The road you took
♪ And how far will you go
♪ And how high will you climb
♪ And when all
In life's unfair ♪
♪ Are you strong enough
To find another way ♪
♪ Another way
♪ A father's way ♪
♪ Ba-ba
♪ Ba-da-ba
♪ Hey. hey
♪ Ba-da-ba-ba
♪ I build a fence around you
♪ In a father's way ♪
♪ Just like the one who used to
Preach to me ♪
♪ Now I've become that way ♪
♪ But you know
♪ How soft lay the hand
♪ That used to strike
To the heart ♪
♪ I will keep knowing
♪ And one day when the fence
Is not so high ♪
♪ The road you took
♪ And how far will you go
♪ And how high will you climb
♪ And when all
In life's unfair ♪
♪ Are you strong enough
To find another way ♪
♪ Another way
♪ A father's way ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ There's no way ♪
♪ That you're gonna stay ♪
♪ I build a fence around you
♪ In a father's way ♪